Rowan Torbitzky-Lane

 $rowan.a.tl@protonmail.com \bullet www.brokenglass.dev \bullet github.com/RowanTL \bullet linkedin.com/in/rowantl/$

Summary

To work at Burlington Northern and Santa Fe Railway as a AI Engineer (Software Engineer I/II). Logically-driven Computer Scientist with a bachelor's degree and 1+ year(s) of personal and professional AI/ML experience. Dedicated to thoroughly reasoning through a problem.

Education

Missouri University of Science and Technology

B.S. Computer Science, with a Minor in Mathematics.

December 2024

Rolla, MO

Summa Cum Laude

Experience

NSF REU Program

May 2024 - October 2024

Missouri University of Science and Technology

Rolla, MO

- Present Research Findings Weekly at Meetings
- Experiment with LLMs and Next-Token Prediction on Genome Sequences
- Clean text data with Scikit-learn and Scikit-bio

Undergraduate Research Assistant

May 2023 - October 2023

Rolla, MO

Center for Intelligent Infrastructure

- Calculate Optical Flow with MATLAB and C++ utilizing Slurm
- Use Django to manage Web Requests
- Program User Interfaces with TypeScript
- Manipulate videos using OpenCV
- Perform Annotations for Image Segmentation Neural Networks
- Participated in Weekly Meetings discussing State of Project

Data Science Co-Op

January 2022 - August 2022

Bridgeton, MO

Hunter Engineering Company

- Utilize Microsoft Excel for Data Annotation
- Train Convolutional Neural Networks with YOLO and PyTorch
- Design and write APIs with FastAPI and Flask
- Containerize said APIs with Docker
- Program internal tooling leveraging Pandas and Microsoft SQL
- Implement workflows into internal Azure DevOps Git repository
- Attend Bi-Weekly Lunch and Learns covering Full-Time Employee Responsibility
- Utilize AWS S3 for Image Storage

Personal Projects

Self-Hosted Linux Server

January 2023 - Present

- Interact with Router Firewall
- Host Wireguard Virtual Private Network
- Manage Reverse Proxy connections with Nginx
- Point Domain Names via A Records
- Built from Components Ordered Online
- Self Host a Git Server
- Train Bird Object Detection Model